KAITLYN TIERNEY

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

+44 7481 488589

k@krtiernev.com

London, UK

Hi! I'm an experienced, well-rounded full-stack web developer. My expertise ranges from HTML (HTML5 and earlier variants), CSS (CSS2, CSS3, including SASS, SCSS, and LESS), modern front-end JavaScript (ES6, and frameworks like Vue, jQuery, Backbone, Angular2, Elm, React, AJAX) and information architecture (JSON, XML). Ruby (+ Rails or Sinatra, RSpec, Capybara) is my server-side language of choice, but I'm keen to work with Scala or more functional languages. Other back-end proficiencies include Python + Django. I'm a big proponent of BDD/TDD, am partial to relational databases (PostgreSQL), and prefer Heroku but am experienced with AWS as well. I also have some familiarity with Node.js (MEAN stack, with MongoDB and Express). Other proficiencies include Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Lightroom, InDesign, Illustrator) integration with third-party APIs (including Twilio, Twitter, Workable, ElasticSearch) and keeping a tidy git commit history. Yes, I'm American, but I hold a valid UK visa with no employment restrictions.

EXPERIENCE

- ➤ Senior Developer, Happy Bear Software (Jan 2017–present)

 Consulting developer for clients include Contagious, Healios, Happity, Unicorn Hunt. Responsible for product management, devops, maintaining legacy code, building (and documenting) APIs, and feature development.

 Recently I've been leading teams of developers on product development, mentoring apprentice developers, and
- ▶ Back-End Developer, Open Utility (2016)
 Back-end development in Python/Django, supporting Open Utility's portfolio of smart energy services.
 Handled bug fixes and built features for our flagship peer-to-peer sustainable energy matching software.

learning about techniques for designing data-intensive applications and machine learning techniques.

- ► Keyholder, BrewDog (2015–16)

 Social media and direct email marketing, beer tastings and private events, maintaining draught system, customer service and sales, staff supervision.
- ► Copy Editor, HY Connect (2014) Editing, proofreading, and copy writing for a variety of advertising clients at a small advertising agency, with a specialization in healthcare-related business.
- ▶ Communications Manager, Center for Health & Social Sciences, Univ. of Chicago (2010–14)
 Planned executed, and hand-coded a new responsive website; content creation and layout design for print and electronic publicity materials including a series of Annual Reports; strategic communications and marketing; branding and identity; editing manuscripts and funding proposals; and hiring and managing student staff.

San Diego Zoo, Assistant Librarian (2006-10)

Website maintenance and SEO optimization (set up Google Analytics and integrated a Google-powered site search bar); cataloging; vendor negotiations and budgeting; managing serial subscriptions (\$75K+ budget); reference support; branding and strategic planning; database design and maintenance.

▶ Kaplan Test Prep, SAT Instructor & Private Tutor (2009–10)

Taught SAT prep classes to high school students and provided private tutoring services to Kaplan clients in need of additional assistance, focusing on test-taking skills and foundational math, science, and writing.

Museum of Photographic Arts, Library Assistant (2006–07)

Cataloging; reference support for curators, educators, and other museum staff; managed circulation; IT support, transitioned catalog to online public-access system, created library blog and web presence.

OTHER WORK

- Coach, Rails Girls London Workshop (2017)
- Coach, codebar London (2017)
- > STEM Mentor, Web-Making for Civic Action Workshop (2014)
- Freelance writing & editing (2010–present)

Author editing for clients including UX Booth, nfc.toys, and Draft Design publications including *Cadence* & *Slang*, a book about interaction design, and *Distance*, a quarterly journal of long-form essays focused on UX and interaction design. Contributing author of long-form pop science articles for *Jezebel* (Gawker Media).

Freelance web development & design (2010–present)

Custom Wordpress theme for a wedding photography business (form styling with GravityForms, TypeKit fonts, parallax, 2012). BikeCHI.org reference for Chicago-based cycling enthusiasts (Joomla, Google calendar integration, 2011). AdamTierney.net, a personal academic publication repository (Skeleton.css, 2010).

REFERENCES

- Najaf Ali, Founder, Happy Bear Software, ali.najaf@gmail.com
- Andy Kilner, CTO, Open Utility, andy@openutility.com

EDUCATION

- Web Development Immersive, General Assembly, London, UK (2015)
- Medical Writing & Editing, University of Chicago Graham School (2012)
- Master of Library & Information Science, San Jose State University, California, USA (2007)
- ▶ Bachelor of Arts in Literatures of the World, University of California, USA (2005)